Michael Kuhn

2902 W McLean Avenue, Chicago, IL 60647 · (847) 323-8376 · mickuhn95@gmail.com

QUALIFICATION SUMMARY

Researcher, Project Manager and Camp Director with over four years of administrative experience. Diligent, creative, perceptive and analytical. Expert digital competency. Organized and thorough researcher. Trained and realized leader, able to manage multiple projects and oversee large teams of individuals. Successful turning around large projects ahead of deadlines, and documenting procedural inefficiencies and implementing effective solutions.

EDUCATION

Michigan State University

May 2018

Bachelor of Science—History, Philosophy and Sociology of Science Lyman Briggs College—*Bioethics Minor* James Madison College—*Science, Technology, Environmental Public Policy Minor* College of Arts and Letters—*Philosophy and Law Minor*

GPA: 3.5

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Scouts BSA Camp Director, Northeast Illinois Council, Vernon Hills, IL, Nov. 2017-Present

- Hired, trained and supervised staff of 60 youth and adults to facilitate diverse program for scouts ages 11-17
- Exercised vision-driven leadership, emphasizing collaboration and individual empowerment *Scouts BSA Camp Commissioner*, Northeast Illinois Council, IL, Oct. 2015-Aug. 2017
- Lead projects, delegated tasks to work teams, and resolved personnel and logistical challenges Scouts BSA Camp Program Area Director and Counselor, Northeast Illinois Council, IL, June 2010-Aug. 2015
- Facilitated programs and events for, trained staff for, and oversaw the Handicraft area
- Fielded customer questions and concerns, utilizing problem solving and prevention skills

Program Coordinator, Northeast Illinois Council, Vernon Hills, IL, Apr. 2019-June 2019

- Developed and updated Square Space website and social media
- Established operating procedures and policies
- Utilized Microsoft Office, MailMerge and PivotTables, to organize and operationalize company data

Research Assistant, Ad Age Datacenter, Crain Communications, Chicago, IL, Mar. 2019-June 2019

- Communicated with S&P 500 companies, verifying affiliated ad agency networks and key brands.
- Surveyed revenue of the largest ad agencies: validated reported figures through cross-referencing previous reports, identifying anomalous reports and making cold calls to agency sources
- Compiled reported revenue and executive updates into a Microsoft Access database
- Edited entries of research team members, and proofread online and printed report
- Exercised time management and organizational skills to multitask and communicate effectively

Electoral Fellow, BallotReady, Chicago, IL, Sept. 2018-Feb. 2019

- Established partnerships with community organizations and influencers across the country
- Developed outreach and social media strategies to maximize public awareness
- Researched candidates and updated a proprietary digital candidate database
- Earned additional responsibilities: trained and supervised remote researchers

SKILLS-ACHIEVEMENTS

- Management Certified: BSA National Camp School, Resident Camp Administration 2016
- Proficient Computer Skills: Python, C#, CSS and HTML, Microsoft Office
- First Aid/CPR Certified
- Eagle Scout